Guide to the Ida Grady scrapbook, 1927-1930 UA.30.01.0066
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ida Grady scrapbook
circa 1927-1930
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Grady, Nancy Ida
UA.30.01.0066
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
Nancy Ida Grady, a native of Asheville, N.C., graduated from Duke University's Woman's College in 1928. Scrapbook contains photographs, postcards, calling cards, invitations, programs, poems, and other memorabilia. Among the programs are several from church services in Durham and Asheville, theatre productions including performances by the Taurian Players and the YWCA, and several guest lectures at Duke. Also present are exams, quizzes, and study questions from courses at Duke in Bible study, religions of China and Japan, Egypt and Mesopotamia.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Nitrate negatives are closed to use; access copies are available on request.
Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use this collection.
Provenance
The Ida Grady scrapbook was received by the University Archives as a gift in 2008.
Biographical Note
Nancy Ida Grady was from Asheville, N.C. and a 1928 graduate of the Woman's College at Duke University. While at Duke, Grady was Secretary-Treasurer of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA), a member of the Historical Society, and Vice-President of the League of Women Voters.
Collection Overview
Scrapbook contains photographs, postcards, calling cards, invitations, programs, poems, and other assorted ephemera and memorabilia. Among the programs are several from church services in Durham and Asheville, theatre productions including performances by the Taurian Players and the YWCA, and several guest lectures at Duke. Also present are exams, quizzes, and study questions from courses at Duke in Bible study, religions of China and Japan, Egypt and Mesopotamia.
The scrapbook has been disassembled and foldered for preservation purposes. Detached clippings and assorted ephemera are housed in envelopes. Nitrate negatives are closed to use; digital scans are available with advance request.
Related Material
Duke University Archives Scrapbook Collection, 1916-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Odessa Massey scrapbook, 1924-1928
Duke University Archives
Alice Craven scrapbook, 1915-1924
Duke University Archives
Maude Brown scrapbook, 1924-1937
Duke University Archives
Virginia Hicks scrapbook, 1921-1925
Duke University Archives
Women college students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Education, Higher -- North Carolina; North Carolina -- Social life and customs -- 20th century; Black-and-white photographs; Ephemera; Cellulose nitrate film; Negatives (photographs); Postcards; Scrapbooks -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University -- Students; Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae; Grady, Nancy Ida; Duke University. Woman's College
- Scrapbook, circa 1927-1930
  - Front Cover (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Loose material inside front cover (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Loose material, page 1 and Clippings, page 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pages 1-2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Loose material, pages 2-3 and Clippings, pages 2-3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pages 3-4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pages 5-6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pages 7-8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Loose material, pages 8-9 and Clippings, pages 8-9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Pages 9-10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Loose material, pages 10-11 and Clippings, pages 10-11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pages 11-12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Loose material, pages 12-13 and Clippings, pages 12-13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pages 13-14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Loose material, pages 14-15 and Clippings, pages 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pages 15-16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Loose material, pages 16-17 and Clippings, pages 16-17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pages 17-18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Loose material, pages 18-19 and Clippings, pages 18-19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pages 19-20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographic negatives, pages 20-21: MOVED TO SERIES 2 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Loose material, pages 20-21 and Clippings, pages 20-21 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, inside back cover (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Back Cover (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Photographic negatives, circa 1927-1930; 2
  Scope and Contents
  Folders contain thirty (30) cellulose nitrate negatives from the Ida Grady scrapbook; descriptions were created by library staff.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Nitrate negatives are closed to use; copies are available on request. Please contact Rubenstein Library Research Services for assistance.
  - man in white shirt and dark tie, holding hat, on lawn against trees, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0001)
    Nitrate negatives are closed to use; copies are available.
    3"x2"
  - woman in white top and skirt with dark scarf around shoulders, on lawn against trees, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0002)
  - woman in white dress and man in white shirt holding up and looking at book, against fence and brick wall, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0003)
  - woman in white dress and man in white shirt and dark tie seated in front of store front, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0004)
  - man in white shirt, dark tie, and hat standing in front of two story brick building, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0005)
  - two women in dark clothing, laughing, with tree trunk behind them, possible beach in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0006)
  - four women kneeling in pose on wood floor in front of wooden cabin, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0007)
  - group of men and women on small boat, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0008)
    3"x2"; another image appears exposed over this
  - woman in dark clothing with tree trunk behind her, possible beach in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0009)
  - group of four women and two men, leaning over, holding books, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0010)
  - group of people on boat or against brick wall, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0011)
  - three women in dresses posing in front of store front, man in doorway in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0012)
    General
    man in background is possibly person of color
    3.5"x2.5"
  - woman and man standing near pole with trees in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0013)
  - woman in foreground looking at two women seated in automobile, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0014)
  - two women and one man seated on sofa against wall with striped wallpaper, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0015)
  - two women and one man seated on bench (?) in street, with line of storefronts and people standing on sidewalk in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0016)
  - woman and man seated together; two images are exposed in same frame, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0017)
  - group of women seated around table with drinks, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0018)
    3.5"x2.5"; another image appears exposed over this
  - two women posing with arms around each other, trees in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0019)
  - group of three women and one man walking along sidewalk, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0020)
  - group of three women and one man standing in semicircle on grass, with trees in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0021)
  - group of four women wearing hats, seated around table with drinks, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0022)
  - three men on long boat with poles, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0023)
  - three men on long boat, one seated and two with poles, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0024)
  - two women and two men seated on sofa or bench, with cushions, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0025)
  - man and woman standing, looking at paper in woman's hands, trees in background, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0026)
  - two women wearing hats, one man, one other person, seated around table with drinks, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0027)
  - river lined with trees, small boat partially behind bush in foreground, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0028)
  - West Duke building on East Campus, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0029)
    4.5"x2.75"
  - man in dark pants, white shirt, dark tie, and hat standing on steps of Duke University East Campus building, circa 1927-1930 (Box 2, Image UA30010066-N-0030)